[enchanting music playing]
[slide clicks]
[older Hero chuckles]
All right. then.
Where were we?
Oh. yeah. that's right.
Now I remember.
"A note about witches."
See. here's the thing
about them.
They're real!
Witches are as real as a rock
in your shoe.
That's the first thing
you need to know.
The second thing
they're here!
And they live amongst us...
[slide clicking]
...side by side. with humans.
In every big city.
in every small town.
For all you know.
a witch might be living right
next door to you right now.
They everywhere!
A witch might be a nurse.
or your teacher.
and you can bet
your sweet patootie
that friendly. little old lady
on the bus
offering you a delicious piece
of salt water taffy
is a witch.
And here's
the most important thing.
The most important thing.
Witches hate children!
A witch spends all her time
thinking up ways
to destroy children.
That's all she thinks about.
"How will I squish
this horrible child?"
[squishing]
A witch gets the same pleasure
from squishing a child
as you get from eating
a bowl of ice cream
covered in butterscotch syrup.
with whipped cream.
chopped nuts.
and a cherry on top.
[children gasp]
[older Hero] My story begins
during the last month of 1968.
Believe it or not.
I was once a young boy.
[slide clicking]
A boy with a mother
and a father.
[slide clicks]
[eerie music playing]
[older Hero]
We lived in Chicago.
And it snows a lot
at Christmastime.
[sirens approaching]
Tricky thing with snow is.
it's slippery.
[man] Take the front! This way!
Mom?
[older Hero]
I was wearing my seat belt.
-Dad?
-[people shouting indistinctly]
Mom!
[older Hero]
Mama and Daddy weren't.
[shouting] Mama! Dad!
Mommy! Dad!
[man] Let's get you
out of here.
[older Hero]  It was during
my eighth Christmas
that I lost
my mother and father.
[Christmas choral
music playing]
[children shouting distantly]
[sniffs] My dear child...
Grandma.
Grandma's here.
[Grandma] Aw.
you gonna be all right.
Here. let me look at you.
Mmm.
I'mma get you out of here.
I packed your things.
I'm gonna take you home.
Home? To my house?
No. darling.
Home to my house.
[engine turns off]
[Reginald] Need any help
bringing these bags
inside. sister?
[Grandma] Oh. no.
thank you. Reginald.
You've done enough already.
Running into you
at the bus station
was a godsend.
-I'm much obliged.
-[Reginald chuckles]
My pleasure. [grunts]
I'll see you in church
come Sunday?
[Grandma] Oh.
you know you will.
Pleasure to make
your acquaintance. young man.
Welcome to Demopolis.
-Thank you. Reggie.
-Sister.
Wait.
Take them shoes off before
you walk on my good rug.
[older Hero]
Grandma was my mama's mama.
A tough lady with a big heart.
The kind that
wouldn't hesitate
to give a spanking
if you deserve it
or a big ol' hug
if you needed it.
[Grandma] I reckon...
you'll be comfy here.
In your mama's old room.
We'll get you
situated tomorrow.
I'm gonna make
some hot chocolate.
Want some?
I'm gonna make some anyway.
in case you change your mind.
[thunder rumbling in distance]
[thunder rumbling]
[rain pattering]
[crying softly]
[weatherman on TV]
High tomorrow. 73.
[Grandma] Young man.
what is wrong with you?
Sitting in here
all by your lonesome.
It's nice out.
You want something to eat?
I just fried some wings.
Nobody turns down my wings.
I'm gonna make you a plate.
[upbeat music playing
on gramophone]
[singing along]  ♪ Now if you
Feel that you can't go on ♪
♪ Because all of your hope
Is gone ♪
♪ And your life is filled
With much confusion ♪
♪ Until happiness
Is just an illusion ♪
♪ And your world around
Is tumblin' down ♪
♪ Darlin' ♪
[chorus singing]  ♪ Reach out ♪
-[man singing]
♪ Come on. girl ♪
-[man]  ♪ Reach on out for me ♪
-♪ Reach out ♪
-Come on. baby. Come on.
-[man]  ♪ Reach out for me ♪
♪ Ha! I'll be there ♪
♪ With a love
That will shelter you ♪
[Grandma] Mmm!
What you waiting for?
Don't feel like eating.
And I don't feel like wasting
all this good food.
What. you think I'm supposed
to feel sorry for you?
Well. I don't.
Do I feel bad?
Yeah.
But not sorry.
Sometimes. whatever the good
Lord needs to teach us
comes in ways we don't see.
But it doesn't mean
we're not supposed
to learn something.
Look here.
This was my baby.
I'd do anything
for her to be here right now.
But the Man Above
had another plan for her.
And whether it seems fair
to me or not.
it doesn't matter.
Sometimes life isn't fair.
It's a hard lesson
for folks to learn
and most people don't have to
learn it this young.
But you do.
You hear me?
[Hero sighs]
Come on now. baby.
you got to eat something.
You like cake?
Well. corn bread
is basically cake.
Mmm-hmm.
Go on. Try it.
[laughing]
[soul music playing]
[knocking at door]
What's his name?
It's a she.
Her name is something
you can ponder.
[playing upbeat melody]
[Grandma humming]
Have you come up with a name
for your mouse yet?
Uh-huh.
Well. tell me.
Don't be keeping me
in suspense.
Aisy.
Lazy?
Well. that mouse
is full of nothing but energy.
She runs all the time
in that wheel.
Not "lazy."
Daisy.
"Daisy." Oh.
I like it.
That's a perfect name for her.
Close your eyes. honey.
[upbeat music playing]
[man singing]  ♪ It's your thing
Do what you wanna do ♪
♪ I can't tell you
Who to sock it to ♪
♪ It's your thing ♪
♪ Do what you wanna do ♪
♪ I can't tell you
Who to sock it to ♪
[older Hero]
And somehow. she did it.
Little by little.
with a tug here
and a pull there.
she brought me
out of my sadness.
[both laughing]
[man singing]
♪ Oh. you need love now ♪
♪ Just as bad as I do ♪
[older Hero]  But even though
my own darkness
was being lifted.
there was another dark shadow
looming nearby.
Very nearby.
I didn't know it.
but I was about to meet
my first witch.
Curses. [hissing]
[coughing]
[man singing]  ♪ All right ♪
♪ Lord have mercy! ♪
[Grandma] Raymond.
Raymond.
You call these fresh?
But we just got them in.
When? Last year?
Look at how yellow they are.
And those brown spots
around the edges.
I'm not gonna waste
good bacon drippings
on these shriveled-up weeds.
Can you get me
some fresh greens
if you don't mind?
Yes. ma'am.
I'll see what we have
in the back.
You do that.
[TV playing indistinctly]
Grandma. can I get these nails
to make Daisy a house?
-[Grandma] Hmm.
-[doorbell jingles]
Well. these aren't galvanized.
You have to use
galvanized nails
so they won't rust.
But galvanized costs
.35 cents more.
Safety first.
Yes. ma'am.
You cut yourself
on a rusty nail.
you can get lockjaw.
Yes. ma'am.
And then I'd have to
flush out your system
with liver oil. garlic juice.
Tabasco sauce.
You wouldn't want to go
through that now. would you?
No. ma'am.
Good.
Remember. safety first.
[coughing]
[older Hero]  Grandma knew how
to fix all kinds of ailments.
She learned from her grandma
how to use herbs and potions
and strange incantations
to make sick people
good as new.
Here in Alabama.
where she grew up.
Grandma was known as a healer.
[whispering] Galvanized.
[in raspy voice] Boy.
[drawling] Boy.
Do you like sweets?
[snake hissing]
She is tame.
Very sweet.
[hissing]
Give her a kiss.
[Grandma coughing]
[Grandma] Young man.
You want those nails.
you better come on...
[continues coughing]
Yes. Raymond.
that's more like it.
[Hero] Grandma.
I need to tell you something!
Not now. son.
But. Grandma...
[coughs] I thought
you wanted those nails.
Forget it. Let's just go.
[continues coughing]
Yeah.
Let's just go.
[thunder rumbling]
Hey.
Son.
what were you
trying to tell me
in the grocery store
this morning?
You were shaking like a leaf.
Don't worry
about that. Grandma.
I just want
you to feel better.
I feel fine.
You just tell me
what you were trying to say.
Looked like you were about
to have a conniption fit.
[sighs heavily]
I don't know what I saw.
It was a scary lady.
She called to me.
But when she did.
when she talked.
her mouth...
Was she wearing gloves?
Long ones. up to her elbows?
Was she wearing a hat?
It looked like she had a towel
on her head or something.
And when she talked.
did her voice
sound ugly and scratchy
like an outhouse door
swinging on a rusty hinge?
Oh. [sighs]
I feared this was happening.
That lady you saw in
the grocery store was no lady.
What you saw
was a witch.
[thunder claps]
A witch?
That's right.
A no-good. rotten. low-down.
sneaky. sneaky witch.
Okay. Okay.
Is this you
and your church friends
trying to play a joke on me?
'Cause if it is.
it's not very funny.
Listen. child.
Witches ain't nothing
to joke about.
I've known children
who no longer exist
as children on this earth.
They were turned.
transformed.
taken by witches.
-[thunder claps]
-[Hero gasps]
I can tell you
about Alice Blue.
Well. Alice Blue and I
were best friends.
We lived across the street
from each other.
We were like sisters.
Inseparable.
We did everything together.
even our chores.
But Alice was a lollygagger.
Alice. quit lollygagging. girl.
It's almost suppertime.
[steam hisses]
[Grandma]  Alice did something
no child should ever do.
She took candy
from a stranger.
[ominous music playing]
I got so scared.
I tore out of there
like greased lightning.
and hightailed it
straight home.
I never should have
left Alice alone.
I knew I shouldn't have.
But I was so scared.
Later that night.
when I saw Alice alive.
I was as happy as a mouse
in a bucket of cheese.
But the very next morning.
all that happiness went away
because it happened.
[whispers]
She started turning.
[shrieks]
[clucking]
[crowing]
[crows]
Alice was chicken-afied.
Chicken-alified.
[clucking continues]
Lordy!
Look at the size
of that chicken.
Y'all seen
where Alice run off to?
She's right...
there.
[woman] What you
talking about. child?
Where'd she go?
[Grandma]  I tried to explain
what I saw.
but everybody was looking
at me like I was crazy.
Finally.
I just shut up about it.
Although. I made it a point
to visit Alice
in her coop every day.
[chicken groans]
Hi. Alice.
[clucking]
[Grandma]  Alice even laid eggs.
Big green ones.
Biggest green eggs
I ever seen.
People said
they were delicious.
What about the witch?
What about her?
Did she go away?
Oh. my. no.
Once a witch come
into your life. it never...
[thunder cracking]
[whispers] Never...
Oh. my. Lord in Heaven.
What am I thinking?
I just told you
we saw a witch today.
A witch in the grocery store.
And what am I doing?
Sitting here
like I'm blind in one eye
and can't see out the other.
wasting precious time
lollygagging.
[thunder continues rumbling]
[older Hero]  Always wondered
what Grandma kept
in that locked closet.
Turns out it was full of
medicinal herbs and elixirs.
and old books
about ancient healing.
Now. my mom always said
Grandma was sort of
a country-type healer.
But now
I was starting to think
she might be
a voodoo priestess.
Child. we need to leave.
-Leave?
-That's right. leave.
It's not safe for us here.
But where we gonna go?
I'll call my cousin. Eston.
Have him make
a reservation for us
at the Grand Orleans
Imperial Island Hotel.
He was the executive chef
there for over 30 years.
He's got pull there.
[chuckles]
He's a star.
His cooking
put that hotel on the map.
It's the swankiest resort
in all of Alabama.
You'll be telling
your grandkids
about your stay in this hotel.
[Hero] How do you know
we'll be safe there?
Because. child.
ain't nothing
but rich white folks
at the Grand Orleans
Imperial Island Hotel.
And witches
only prey on the poor.
the overlooked.
the kids they think
nobody's gonna make a fuss
about if they go missing.
Go pack!
[Hero] Grandma. are there
witches in every city?
[Grandma] Every city.
every state. every country.
And there's
a secret society of witches
in every country
called a coven.
That's just like a Rotary Club
but for witches.
They all get together
in one place
and gossip about
who they put spells on.
or trade potion secrets.
and whatnot.
But most important.
they receive orders
from the Grand High Witch.
The Grand High Witch?
The Grand High Witch. yeah.
She's the ruler of them all.
All-powerful. pure evil.
and without a stitch of mercy.
Yeah. Legend has it.
she was hatched
on the frozen tundra
of Norway.
Now. take a look at that.
What. you just
gonna stand there
and stare at me all day?
Can I help you?
You can unload this car while
I check in to this here hotel.
Yes. ma'am.
Here's the key.
Oh. and...
No.
You keep your money. ma'am.
And enjoy yourself.
I think I will.
[older Hero]  Grandma was right
about this hotel.
It sure was fancy.
She brought us
to the Gulf of Mexico
to get away from that witch.
But she had no idea what
we were about to step into.
[Daisy sniffing]
[whispers]
Be careful with the mouse.
-[man] No.
-[woman] For God's sake.
I think you're being
extremely unreasonable.
[man] No. Deidre.
For the last time.
I will not have that woman
in my house.
[woman] Oh.
she's very good company.
[man] Absolutely not. Deidre.
[woman] Oh. for God's sake.
Bruno. your face.
Obviously can't
take you anywhere.
[receptionist]
Here you are. ma'am.
Come on. we got our key.
We are in room 766.
[Hero] Sounds like
a good room.
[Grandma coughing]
-You okay. Grandma?
-[coughs]
That's the first time
you coughed
since we left the house.
-Can I help you. madam?
-[coughs]
Oh! You must be
Eston's cousins.
Yes. he insisted
that you stay in room 766.
That's the Magnolia.
This is one of
our most lovely junior suites.
[Grandma chuckles]
And aren't you
a lucky fella? Hmm?
It's not every day
that a young gentleman
such as yourself is fortunate
to come and stay in such
a fine hotel as this now.
is it?
Come on. Gatsby.
Let's go.
Let's go find our room.
Would you like me to show you?
-It's on the fourth floor.
-[Grandma] Mmm.
[Hero] Grandma.
if we're on the fourth floor.
why is it number 7-6-6?
Because the man who built
this hotel was a numerologist.
He believed
numbers have meaning.
I know a little something
about numbers.
Seven and six together
means a test is coming.
Two sixes mean abundance.
So. it look like
a big test might be coming.
[marching with
synchronized steps]
Well. hello there.
The Grand Orleans
Imperial Island Hotel
welcomes you and your lovely
group of benefactresses.
Uh. I would just like to say
that we applaud
your innumerable.
uh. philanthropic...
-acts and. um...
-[cat purring]
And. um...
I'm sorry. madam.
but the hotel has
a very strict no-pet policy.
[with Eastern European accent]
You seem like the sort of man
who loves a precious.
Don't you. Mister...
Stringer. R. J. Stringer III.
Hotel Manager.
Thank you
for making an exception.
-Mr. R. J. The Hotel Manager.
-Stringer.
Yes. but I haven't yet...
But I didn't agree...
So. tell me something.
Mister...
-Stringy?
-Stringer.
Hotel man.
-Manager.
-The third.
-Yeah.
-I know you love kitties.
-[cat hisses]
-[chuckles uneasily]
But what do you think of...
mice?
Mice?
Yeah. Mice.
What would you do
if there were mice
running all around
in this hotel?
Well. I can assure you. madam.
there would
never be any mice...
[shushes] But if there were?
Hypothetically?
Mmm. Oh. hypothetically.
Yes. I suppose.
well. I would. uh...
I would call the exterminator.
Exactly!
You see. girls?
He would call
the exterminator!
Just like any normal human
with his head
screwed on right.
he would exterminate
those brats.
Uh... Rats.
We would exterminate the rats.
[Grandma]  Evil.
[thunder crashing]
There's no other way
to describe them.
Pure. unvarnished evil.
That's what witches are.
-[thunder cracking]
-[Grandma coughing]
[hoarsely] Now. you see
this here cough of mine?
It was likely brought on
by a witch.
Probably that one you saw
in the grocery store.
Really? A witch
can make you cough?
Oh. you bet
your sweet patootie they can.
Grandma. how can you tell
a real witch from
Well. first of all. witches
aren't really women at all.
They're demons in human shape.
That's why if you look closely
at a witch.
you'll notice the corners
of her mouth is elongated.
stretching almost
up to her ears.
and that's usually hidden
with pancake makeup.
And a real witch always
wears gloves. Always.
Because a real witch
doesn't have hands.
She's got claws.
[Hero] Claws?
[thunder cracking]
And they don't have toes. Ooh.
Their ugly feet look like
their toes got chopped off
with an axe.
And all witches are bald.
As bald as a boiled egg.
So. they wear wigs.
And it gives them nasty sores.
"Wig rash."
the witches call it.
Mmm! And it makes them crazy.
So. gloves.
wigs.
Is that everything?
Nose-holes.
-Nose-holes?
-Yeah. Nostrils.
Nose-holes.
Witches have larger nose-holes
than normal people.
When they need
to sniff out a child.
those nose-holes can grow out
as big as eight inches
in diameter.
[thunder cracks]
But. mind you. children
smell horrible to witches.
[Hero] Even if the kid
just had a bath?
[chuckles]
That makes it worse.
A freshly clean kid smells
like dog poop to a witch.
-Dog poop?
-That's right.
And the cleaner the kid.
the poopier he smells
to a witch.
Maybe I should
stop taking baths.
Child. don't test me.
Can a witch come in here
and get us while we sleep?
No.
Not at all.
Witches never do
silly things like
climbing drainpipes or
breaking into people's houses.
Besides. they have no idea
where we are.
Okay. but I'm still
a little scared.
Over here. come on.
little man.
There we go.
Get some sleep.
[thunder rumbling]
[hisses]
[cat purring]
Hmm?
Really?
[wincing]
Mmm.
-[thunder cracking]
-[chuckles]
[people chattering in distance]
[older Hero]  The next morning.
the sun was shining
and the air was crisp
I kept quiet as a mouse
so Grandma could sleep in.
and I took it upon myself
to order her
some room service breakfast.
[Grandma] Mmm. mmm. mmm.
Here's your breakfast.
Grandma.
Scrambled eggs.
chicken fried steak.
hominy grits.
pecan sticky buns.
rhubarb strawberry jam.
and a pitcher
of sweet iced tea with mint.
Oh. that sure smells special.
Oh. mercy. I slept in late.
Phew.
Well. thank you for ordering
me breakfast. darling.
I gave the room service guy
a half a dollar tip.
Was that okay?
That's mighty
gentlemanly of you.
[coughs]
Grandma. are you okay?
I'm fine.
Just a little tickle.
Grab Grandma
that glass of tea. [coughs]
And listen. Grandma's gonna
take it easy today.
But I want you to get outside
and run around.
Go down to the water.
Have fun.
I was thinking I would do
some training with Daisy.
Oh! Well. take her with.
Just don't let her get
too close to the water.
I wouldn't want
some big old sea snake
to grab ahold of her.
Sea snake?
I'm just joshing.
There ain't no sea snakes.
You go on now. Have fun.
And don't worry about me.
I'm fine.
[older Hero]  Even though I knew
Grandma was kidding
about the sea snakes.
I didn't wanna
take any chances.
so we stayed inside.
And wouldn't you know.
we came upon the big ballroom
where it turns out
the International Society
for the Prevention of Cruelty
to Children folks
were gonna have
their conference.
[door creaking]
Hey!
You there!
And what are you doing?
Breaking and entering?
Looking for a quiet spot.
For what?
Training.
Training what?
Cool. Super.
What's his name?
It's a she.
And her name is Daisy.
-Can I hold her?
-[Daisy squeaking]
She's not too comfortable
around strangers.
Can she do any tricks
or anything?
We were just about
to do some training.
Wanna watch?
What time is it?
A nice lady told me
to meet her here at 12:25.
She said she would give me
six bars of Swiss chocolate.
What's your name?
I'm...
Bruno Jenkins!
I've been looking for you
everywhere. young man.
Your father is furious.
Hello. Mother.
This is my new friend.
Nice to meet you.
Look at your hands.
they're filthy!
Look at your shirt!
It's a complete mess!
-Come with me.
-Ow!
What have you been doing?
Running around
in a sausage factory?
[door creaking]
[older Hero]  The room
was completely empty.
A perfect place for me
and Daisy to do our training.
And I figured.
if all the Prevention
of Cruelty to Children people
showed up.
they would
probably look kindly
on a young mouse trainer
who was just
going about his business.
[clangs]
Jeez. that scared
the crap out of me.
[switches clicking]
So. here we are.
Here is the Le Grand
Imperial Ballroom
or Le Salon Grande.
as we call it.
Well. actually
we call it the Mural Room
because of all these
beautiful murals...
I was told there is only
one door in and out. yeah?
Yeah. Yes.
There's. uh. only that door
there. in and out.
and which. of course.
does not make
the fire marshal very happy.
So. don't you go
starting any fires.
This room will do.
[Mr. Stringer] Right. so...
[marching with
synchronized steps]
Yeah. so. if there's any...
Is there anything else
-that you ladies--
-No.
-No?
-Bye-bye.
Oh. all right.
[sniffing]
[woman] Saoirse.
secure the room!
Okay. you so-called ladies.
Prepare for removal.
-[whispers] Wake up.
-[snake hissing]
[hissing]
[sniffing]
[grunts]
Okay. you trussed-up
succubines.
you may remove your gloves.
[dramatically]
You may remove your shoes.
And...
you may remove your wigs!
[sighing in relief]
[whispers]
They're all witches.
[older Hero]  My blood ran cold
as I started
to get real scared.
Here I was.
trapped in a room with a bunch
of bald-headed witches!
And the mean one.
the bald-head honcho
who was standing
right above me.
the one who was
giving all the orders.
as soon as I got
a good look at her.
I knew instantly
who she had to be.
[crunches]
She's the Grand High Witch.
[thuds]
[snarls]
[croakily] Witches.
Witches.
You are a heap
of good-for-nothing worms!
[in normal voice]
This morning.
I'm having my breakfast
and I'm looking out
the window. at the beach.
and what am I seeing? Hmm?
[croakily] What am I seeing?
[in normal voice]
I'm seeing dozens...
I'm seeing hundreds...
I'm seeing hundreds
of repulsive little brats
playing in the sand.
and it's putting me
right off my food!
So...
Here are my orders.
I want every child
in the world...
rubbed out!
Squashed. squirted.
and frittered!
Your Excellency.
do you have a plan?
How can we possibly
wipe out every child?
[witch yelps]
[witches gasp]
That was actually
a good question.
Insubordinate
but a good question.
Of course I have a plan.
I want each of you to return
to your pathetic little town.
And open...
[inhales sharply]
a candy store.
And in this store
you will sell
only the highest quality.
tastiest candy.
Now. you're
probably wondering.
"Where do I get the money
to buy a candy shop?"
Well. I have
thought of that too.
In my room. room number 666.
I have a steamer trunk
filled with brand-new.
crisp $100 bills!
Room 666.
[Grand High Witch]
Remember that room number 666
and your shops will sell
only the highest quality.
tastiest candy.
And...
We use Formula Number 86
Delayed Action Mouse Maker!
[witches] Ooh!
One drop of Mouse Maker
in a piece of candy
will transform
a dirty little child
into a mouse in one hour!
[witches] Ah!
Two drops
will transform the disgusting
little brat in 30 minutes.
And three drops
is instantaneous.
An instant mouse!
[rattling]
[giggling] Oh.
Oh. no. no. no.
-[rattling continues]
-[shushing]
Shut up.
So.
less than an hour ago.
I found a repulsive smelly
little boy in the lobby
and I gave him
an outrageously expensive
bar of Swiss chocolate.
A chocolate bar
that was laced with one drop
-of my Number 86...
-Oh. no.
[Grand High Witch] ...Delayed
Action Mouse Maker potion!
Bruno.
And I told
the greedy little brat
to meet me here at 12:25.
So. in less than 10 minutes.
all you pathetic witches will
see what a true genius I am!
[witches chanting]
Genius! Genius! Genius!
-[cackling]
-[witches continue chanting]
Quiet!
[chanting stops]
[sniffing]
[continues sniffing]
[growls]
[witches gasping]
[snake hissing]
-[knocking at door]
-[Bruno] Where's my chocolate?
It's the greedy little cretin.
-Quick! Put on your wigs!
-[Bruno] Hey. are you in there?
Welcome. you...
fine. handsome man. [sniffs]
We've been waiting.
[Grand High Witch] Darling boy.
I have your chocolate for you.
[Grand High Witch whistles]
You promised me
six bars of chocolate.
I only see one in your hand.
Hmm... You see. ladies.
not only is he fat and stupid
but greedy too. [chuckles]
-[witches snicker]
-Mmm.
[witches gasp in awe]
[Grand High Witch]
That's right. little man.
Here is your
delicious chocolate.
Come and get it.
Get ready. girls.
Ten seconds.
Give me my chocolate.
Give it to me.
[Grand High Witch]
It's right here. my darling.
[whispering]
Daisy. what do we do?
[Bruno] Give me.
Give me.
[Grand High Witch]
Five seconds.
[Bruno] Give me my chocolate.
Give it to me.
Three...
-Give me it. Give me. Give me!
-[Grand High Witch] Two...
One...
-[clock clangs]
-[bones cracking]
Ignition!
[cackling]
[Saoirse laughing]
[smoke hissing]
[gasps]
That smelly brat.
that horrid louse
has been transformed...
She's done it.
She's a genius.
[Grand High Witch]
...into a lovely little mouse!
[laughs]
What's the big idea?
Where's my chocolate?
Squish him!
Whoa!
-[witches clamoring]
-Squish him! Kill him!
[Bruno panting]
He's right there.
[Hero] They turned Bruno
into a mouse
and now they're trying
to squish him.
I'll fetch him.
Did you just talk?
It's a swarm!
They're everywhere!
[Grand High Witch] Get him.
Where is he? Where is he?
[Bruno yelping]
Gosh! You're a giant.
Why are you so big?
I'm not big.
You're little. I'm normal.
How can I be little?
Because you're a mouse.
A witch put a spell on you.
Witch? What witch?
Ah-ha! I knew it!
Dog dropping!
-[Hero] Help!
-[Grand High Witch] Grab him.
-[Hero] Help! Help me!
-Hold him down.
-Flip him. Gag position.
-Help! Help!
Open his trap.
Open it.
[croakily] Okay.
That's how you wanna play.
we'll play
the Shakespeare way.
[grunts]
One drop...
[smoke hissing]
[muffled groaning]
[Grand High Witch] Two...
[breathes heavily]
Blast off.
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
[screaming]
[smoke hissing]
[gasps]
[panting weakly]
Aren't you
a cute little mouse?
[growling]
[screams]
-[Bruno gasps]
-Who has the mallet?
-Here! Here!
-Get the mallet.
[witch] Where's the mallet?
I'm not afraid of nothing.
[Grand High Witch] I have him.
Where's the mallet?
Come on. Give it to me.
Give it to me.
-[crunches]
-[screams]
[screaming]
[Hero] Run. Bruno. run!
So. you're a mouse too?
-Now I've got you.
-[yelps]
[yelping]
Four legs. Bruno.
Four legs.
[panting]
Rats! A dead end!
[gasps] Run. Bruno. run!
No!
[screaming]
[screams]
[sobbing]
[all grunting]
Ow. my back.
What happened to us?
Why are we mouses?
-[Daisy and Hero] "Mice."
-Whatever.
There's a convention of
witches here in the hotel.
and they have an evil potion.
They put it in your chocolate.
My chocolate? Crikey!
They always spike
the chocolate.
It's standard
evil witch procedure.
Wait. You were a kid too?
A girl.
Do I look like
a baby goat to you?
[bleating]
Nope. a mouse.
What are we going to do?
I don't want to be a mouse.
I like being
a portly little kid.
"Child."
Whatever.
All right.
we have to find my grandma.
She knows
everything about witches.
She'll know what to do.
Come on.
Two crab salads.
What are you doing?
Wow. look at
all that lovely food.
Okay. here's what we do.
You see that vent?
I bet that'll get us
to the lobby. Let's go.
[chef] Pick that up.
That's white truffle.
You have any idea
how much white truffle costs?
Wipe it off
and put it in the sauce.
What is this?
You call that puffed?
Let's get some more hands
in here.
[elevator bell dings]
[Daisy whispering]
So. now what?
Look. all we need to do is
make our way to the elevator.
then up to the fourth floor.
Come on.
[grunts]
Hey. a little help.
[all grunt]
Crikey.
-Hurry up.
-This way.
I just realized
something. y'all.
How exactly do we
reach the button
-Floor?
-Four. please.
Come on.
There's my room. 766.
This way.
[Hero grunting]
[sighs] She's never
going to hear us.
[gasps] A doorbell.
Come on.
[grunting]
[grunts]
Crikey!
All right.
We make a human ladder.
You mean a mouse ladder?
Right. a mouse ladder.
[all grunting]
Ow! Ow.
[straining]
I got... I got...
-I got it!
-[doorbell dings]
-[Daisy screaming]
-[Hero grunting]
Help me!
Ahhh. great balls of fire.
don't let me fall!
[grunting]
-[Bruno] Phew.
-Follow me. boys.
[screaming]
[screams]
[yelping]
[kids yelping]
[chambermaid] Mice!
Mice! Mice! [screams]
They everywhere!
[squeals]
[chambermaid screaming
and sobbing]
[gasps]
Grandma. it's me.
your grandson.
My grandson...
Is that you. boy?
Yes. Grandma. it's me.
Oh... Oh.
Is it really you?
It's really me.
-What happened?
-It was the Grand High Witch.
The Grand High Witch?
Oh. Lord.
not the Grand High Witch.
Yes. She mouse-afied me.
And the whole hotel
is full of witches.
They're having a witch
convention or something.
You been through so much.
you don't need this.
Grandma's so. so sorry.
Grandma.
please get off the floor
and put me
on the coffee table.
-How do I do that?
-Pick me up.
Pick you up?
Yeah. just like
I pick up Daisy.
Right.
I can't believe
this happened to you.
Believe me.
things could be a lot worse.
They could?
[Hero] Oh. Grandma.
by the way.
this is my friend.
Bruno Jenkins.
He's now a mouse too.
but he used to be
a chubby. little English kid.
You could've just stopped at.
"This is my friend. Bruno."
[Grandma] I'm so sorry. Bruno.
Those nasty. evil witches
got you too. huh?
Yes. They got me good
and proper.
It's been an awful day.
-Anybody else hungry?
-Ahem!
Oh. and Daisy used to be
a kid... A girl too.
[Grandma] Why didn't you
say something before. darling?
Because it can be
very dangerous
for a mouse to talk.
Most people don't understand
and they get scared.
I almost said something
the other night
when you told the story
about Alice Blue
getting turned into a chicken.
but I thought better of it.
So. some wicked. evil witch
mouse-afied you.
Yes. ma'am. four months ago.
On the very same afternoon
I ran away from the orphanage.
Well. what happened was.
a kind lady...
Well. I thought she was kind.
Anyway. she offered me
a chocolate bar.
and before I knew it. poof!
I was transformed.
Then. faster than a hot knife
cuts through butter.
a panhandler scoops me up
and sells me to a pet store
so he could buy food.
Yum!
I'm so sorry. Daisy.
Mary. Uh. my real name
is Mary.
Mary. That's a pretty name.
Excuse me.
All this talk about food
is making me really hungry.
Can I have
one of those grapes?
[Grandma] So. it was
the Grand High Witch.
and she's in this very hotel?
We got to do something to turn
you back. Make this right.
The Grand High Witch
has a room full of potion.
And she's gonna use it
to turn every kid in the world
into a mouse.
We have to help them.
-[doorbell rings]
-[Bruno gasps]
-Who is it?
-[man] Hotel maintenance.
[whispers] Quick. hide.
Here. Hop in my knitting tote.
Keep your heads down.
Yes.
I'm sorry to
bother you. ma'am.
but we got a report of
a possible rodent infestation.
Rodent infestation?
In a hotel this expensive?
That's crazier than
a hog on slaughter day.
Yes. ma'am.
It's probably nothing.
The maid who said
she saw the rodents
has a tendency to be
a bit high-strung. [chuckles]
-Mmm.
-But. to be on the safe side.
I thought
I'd lay these here traps.
-if you don't mind.
-Okay.
-We put them in all the rooms.
-Mmm-hmm.
Just to be safe.
So. uh. what are they? Mice?
Oh. No. ma'am.
Maid said she saw
a swarm of huge. ugly rats.
At least a dozen of them.
Goodness. a dozen?
Well. it's like I said.
she has a tendency to be
a bit high-strung. [chuckles]
[sniffs]
Fresh Wisconsin cheddar.
Drives them rodents
plumb crazy.
They can't resist it.
[Bruno] Mmm... [grunts]
Anyway. you hear any
of these traps start snapping.
give me a call.
I sure will.
[man] That's right.
Don't you know anything?
Grapes can hurt a mouse.
[Grandma] All right. you three.
You stay away from
those traps. you hear?
If we could just get our hands
on some of that potion.
I might be able
to reverse-engineer it.
Make it a potion
that turns mice into children.
I always travel with
my anti-hex herbs and salts.
But whoever knows where
that wicked. evil witch is.
We do. She's in room 666.
We heard her tell
all those witches
to meet her in room 666
right after dinner.
And we're in room 766.
Room 666 is right below us.
Good Lord!
That evil sorceress is living
right beneath us?
Yes. And here's what we do.
We wait for the Grand High
Witch to leave her room.
then we use
Grandma's knitting wool
as a rope to lower me down
to the Grand High Witch's
balcony.
I grab a bottle of potion.
Grandma hoists me back up.
she reverses the spell.
and ta-da!
We're kids again.
Young man. you think
all that up just now?
Popped right into my head.
-[kids screaming playfully]
-[beach crowd chattering]
[splutters]
[retches]
[Grand High Witch]
Vile. filthy brats.
You make me puke!
[groans] Hades.
it's getting so bad.
I can't even enjoy
a glass of wormwood.
She's the Grand High Witch.
all right.
[both gasp]
-[Hades meows]
-[groans]
Grandma. that's the potion.
She's keeping it on ice.
Yeah. it's exactly
what we need.
[Grand High Witch] Hades. come.
-[Hades growls]
-We are late for tea.
Teatime. Perfect.
Now look. all we need
is one bottle of potion.
So. grab one as fast
as you can and hurry on back.
No telling when that monster
is fixing to return.
I know you're
likely scared. baby.
I'm not scared. Grandma.
I don't know why.
but ever since I was turned
into a small mouse.
little things
don't scare me anymore.
Okay. Hold on tight.
[sniffing]
[Hero grunting]
[grunts]
[straining]
[grunting]
[doorknob clicks]
[Hero gasps]
[door closes]
[panting]
[Hades growling]
[Grand High Witch]
I can't believe
they won't let my precious
into the dining room.
This fleabag. roach-trap hotel
discriminates
against everything.
Money.
Money. money. money.
Oh. Hades.
why. in this disgusting
human world.
do you need money
for everything?
[coughs]
[sighs]
[gags]
Disgusting. filthy lucre.
[whimpers and sniffles]
[blubbering]
[grunts]
He's ready.
[gasping]
[both gasp]
Well. well. well. well.
Why is this wool here.
I wonder?
Oh. [chuckles nervously] Hello.
I just dropped my knitting
over the balcony.
But it's all right.
Thank goodness I still have
a hold of it on this end.
Well. I'm just gonna
go ahead on and...
And pull it on up.
I'll be out of your way.
-Let go.
-[breathing shakily]
I know you.
Me?
I don't think so.
I have seen you before.
I remember your face.
You mighta seen me
in the lobby. maybe.
No. no. no. no. no.
Not in the lobby.
I remember you from...
-[doorbell dings]
-[yells] What? Who is it?
[Mr. Stringer]
It's Mr. Stringer III.
Hotel Manager.
[Grand High Witch] Curses!
[scoffs]
[Mr. Stringer]
You want me to remove
the children from the beach?
[Grand High Witch]
I want them removed.
[Mr. Stringer] Well. I'll...
I'll see what I can do.
Madam. I procured this.
uh. for you today.
I thought you might like it.
It's a kitty carrier.
And I thought
you could put your feline
friend in there and you can
transport him
all over the hotel.
including the dining room.
Thought you might like that.
Well.
let me tell you something.
Mister Cat-Cage-Procurer.
I will never. ever
allow my precious puss
to be...
[Hades yowls]
[Hades growls and purrs]
Well. look at that.
He likes it in there.
[grunts quietly]
Oh. madam. I almost forgot.
Regarding your ladies' dinner
this evening.
we have neglected
to select a soup.
Now. there are two choices.
One is our
Cajun spice crab Creole.
and the other one is our
plantation kitchen split pea.
[inhales sharply]
Which one is cheaper?
Well. madam.
I'm sure you will appreciate
that the crab is fresh
and it is...
-[shouts] Which one?
-[groans]
[sighs]
Plantation kitchen split pea.
That's the one.
Then we will have
the split pea soup.
Yes. madam.
[Grand High Witch] And...
no garlic in the soup.
No what?
Garlic.
No garlic?
Did I stutter?
No garlic.
My women.
all suffer from a selective
food avoidance disorder.
Picky eaters.
Yes. madam.
As you wish.
I will inform the chef.
You do that.
I'll let myself out.
Well. my precious.
since you enjoy being
in that cage so much.
-you can stay in it!
-[snarls]
Traitor!
[Grandma]  Mouse Maker potion.
A drop of hyssop...
[fizzing]
A smidgen of mugwort...
And now.
a dash of healing water.
straight from Lourdes.
This is the most powerful
healing water there is.
Okay.
Now let's all join hands
and bow our heads.
[liquid fizzing]
Well. I'll be...
Not much more to say
than that. [sighs]
We had to try something. kids.
This witch's power
is far greater
than my little home remedies.
Evil power.
[Grandma] And strong.
Much stronger than me.
Please don't cry. Grandma.
It'll be okay.
[Grandma] I'm sorry. children.
It's not your fault. Grandma.
Sometimes things just happen.
Yeah. they do.
I actually don't mind
being a mouse.
I get to hang out
with my new friends all day.
don't have to go
to school anymore.
and I don't have to learn
how to drive.
which means I'll never
get into an accident.
Oh. child.
Come here.
Grandma. will you still
take care of me?
Even if I stay a mouse?
[Grandma] Of course
I will. darling.
Doesn't matter who you are
or what you look like.
so long as somebody loves you.
And I always will.
What about my friends?
Can they stay too?
Well. of course.
If they want to.
but don't forget.
they all have loved ones
I'm not so sure about that.
Don't be a fool.
I'm sure they love you.
My mother thinks I'm clumsy.
and my father complains
that I'm always hungry.
Well. maybe this will
help them love you
for who you are.
not for who you ain't.
You're fortunate
to have parents. Bruno.
Some of us don't.
But we're gonna be okay.
We have Grandma.
And she'll
always be our family.
And for that
we are very blessed.
But what I wanna know
is why are we standing
around here lollygagging?
How are we gonna stop
those horrible witches
from turning
more children into mice?
She's right.
We got to do something.
I know what we'll do.
I sneak into the kitchen with
the Number 86 Mouse Maker.
then I slip the potion
into the witches' pea soup
and turn them all into mice.
Are you sure about this.
little man?
This sounds like
it could be a very dangerous
and scary mission.
Trust me. Grandma.
I can handle it.
[dramatic music playing]
I'll meet you
in the lobby bar.
Bruno and Daisy
know which vent.
Be careful. darling.
I will. Grandma.
[sous chef] Hurry up there!
[chef] The pea soup is ready.
No garlic.
[sous chef] I got the soup.
no garlic. Chef.
coming right up.
[chef] Where are my prawns?
This is not a prawn.
this is a shrimp.
You don't know the difference
between a shrimp and a prawn?
Count the pincers.
Un. deux.  One. two.
Let's start ladling out
that soup.
Come on. you people.
-[chef rushing in French]
-[sous chef] Yes. Chef.
[grunting]
[chef in English]
What are you doing. huh?
[sous chef] I'm getting
the prawns ready.
[chef] Don't tell me
that's a prawn.
-I'm a crustacean expert.
-[sous chef] This is a prawn.
[chef] I've been
sauteing prawns for 30 years
and I only use butter.
-[sous chef] Only butter?
-[chef] Never oil.
I don't give a damn
about what nutritionists say.
They are
the ruination of cuisine.
Always butter.
butter only.
[chef speaking French]
[in English]
Where are my prawns?
Who do I have to get
some prawns around here?
[chef shouts in French]
[in English] Let's start
ladling out that soup.
[sous chef] Yes. Chef.
[chef] Are you crying?
There's no crying
in my kitchen.
[gasps]
Chef. this soup
needs some garlic.
Absolutely no garlic.
Stringer's orders.
Grease fire.
[sous chef] We got fire
blankets under those sinks.
[chef] Are those my prawns
that just exploded?
[grunts]
Forget the prawn. just throw
some shrimp in there.
-You idiots don't know how...
-[bubbling]
[chuckles]
Someone get me a sharp knife
so that I can kill myself.
[chef grunts]
Somebody call an exterminator.
Look. there's my mother
and father.
That's your mother and father?
As I live and breathe.
Bruno. I think it's time
to say hello to your parents.
Are you mad?
Right here in the bar?
There's no time
like the present.
[Grandma clears throat]
Excuse me.
are you Mr. and Mrs. Jenkins?
Can we help you?
I'm afraid I have some.
well. strange news
about your son. Bruno.
What about Bruno?
Where is he?
Maybe we can go somewhere
a bit more private.
[Mr. Jenkins] Private?
Why do we have to be private?
It's not an easy thing
for him to explain.
He'd be much more comfortable
we all went up to your room.
No. no. look here. madam.
I'm perfectly comfortable
exactly where I am.
So. either you tell me
where I can find Bruno
or you just
leave us alone now.
[Grandma] Well...
-got him right here.
-[shrieks]
That's a mouse! A mouse!
What in God's name
is wrong with you?
Get that filthy rodent
out of here!
No. no. no. no. This is Bruno.
-Bruno. say something to them.
-[Mrs. Jenkins screaming]
"Say something"?
Are you insane?
Get away from us
before I call the manager.
Quit all this hollering.
This is your son. Bruno.
Manager! Someone get me
the manager.
This woman has just scared
my wife half to death.
She's walking around
with rats in her handbag.
[sighs]
Bruno. why didn't
you say something?
My father hates it when I talk
with my mouth full.
[Hero] Psst! Grandma.
Down here.
There you are.
Thank the Lord.
So. how'd it go?
Soup is on.
Look! The pea soup.
[waiter] Here we are.
garlic free.
Excuse me. madam.
may I have a word with you?
Please. this way.
Just over here.
Um...
You wouldn't happen
to be carrying around a mouse
on your person now. would you?
-A mouse?
-Mmm-hmm.
Why on earth would I
be carrying around a mouse?
Does this have anything to do
with all the rat traps
being set up
all over this hotel?
Rat traps?
Is this your pathetic idea
of a smoke screen?
Accusing your guests
of carrying around mice
to hide the fact that this
hotel has a mouse infestation.
Shh. No... Shh. What?
I'll tell you this.
For what this hotel
is costing me.
I better not see
a single mouse.
Not even a tiny. cute one.
Yes. madam. I'm so...
My mistake. I'm sorry.
Luther.
Would you please show
this lady to our finest table?
Certainly.
This way.
Apologies. madam.
-I. it's just...
-[Grandma] Mmm.
Our finest table. madam.
Oh. uh. thank you. Luther.
I'm sure
your finest table
in this lovely establishment
is this one right here
next to the kitchen.
I always prefer
a table near the exit
so I can get out fast.
-Of course.
-[Grandma] Mmm.
[footsteps approaching]
[Bruno grunts]
[Hero whispers]
Check it out.
They love the soup.
[waiter] Have you decided?
Uh. yes. I think
I'll have the jambalaya.
Excellent. And would you like
something to start?
[Grandma] Mmm...
Well. that pea soup
those fancy ladies are eating
looks good.
I'll have that.
I'm sorry.
That soup is reserved
strictly for that group
of lady guests only.
If I may.
that large party suffers
from a severe garlic allergy.
So. they have requested their
soup be prepared garlic free.
It is very bland.
Practically inedible.
[witches slurping]
[Grandma] I see.
That sounds disgusting.
[waiter] May I suggest
the Cajun spice crab Creole?
It's one
of our signature dishes.
[Grandma] Uh. sounds...
[waiter] Yes?
Uh. the... The shrimp Creole
will be fine.
[waiter] You mean
the crab Creole?
Yes. yes. the crab Creole.
[waiter] Very good.
[quietly] Keep your heads down.
we got company.
[whispers] Pigtails.
I'm sorry?
[drawling] Pigtails.
You wore pigtails.
[Grandma] Do I know you?
Many years ago.
in a shabby little town.
A shabby little town
right here in Alabama.
You wore pigtails.
And you got away from me.
Remember?
But I got
that horrid little friend
of yours.
Remember...
[gagging]
[clucking]
-[giggling]
-Quick. mouse ladder.
[all grunt]
It was you.
You were the filthy witch
who turned Alice.
[wheezing]
Aw...
-That's a nasty...
-[witch whimpering]
[Saoirse gobbling
convulsively]
-[witches gasping]
-[smoke hissing]
[witches whimpering]
-[screeching]
-[witches screaming]
[smoke hissing]
[witches screaming]
What are you doing?
-[squeaking]
-[all screaming]
Grandma. look.
[all giggle]
Attaboy.
[witches screaming]
[grunts angrily]
[screeching]
[all screaming]
-[all laughing]
-High five. baby!
Mmm-hmm! That's some
serious ratification.
[rats squeaking]
[people whimpering]
[man] Oh. my God!
It's on my leg!
Ooh. Lordy.
hell's a-poppin'. [chuckles]
[screaming continues]
[witch grunting]
Come here.
you nasty critter...
[screeching]
[screaming]
[grunting]
[Mr. Stringer] Get it off!
Get it off!
-Get it off!
-[crunches]
[screaming]
[all gasp]
Come on. kids.
It's time to skedaddle.
[Mr. Springer continues
screaming and grunting]
Somebody call
the exterminator!
[key jingling]
Good job.
Ooh. ooh...
Look at all this potion.
Kids. we got
to grab every bottle.
Hey. Grandma. what about him?
[Hades yowling]
I'll call the manager to let
him out once we out of here.
Oh. I dropped some.
I'll get it. Grandma.
[all grunting]
[sniffs] Whoa. that cheese
smells awfully good.
[all gasp]
[objects rustling]
[all whimpering quietly]
-[Grand High Witch growls]
-[gasps]
[grunts]
Look what you made me do.
You think you're so clever.
breaking into my room
with a stolen key?
But everyone knows they keep
a spare key at the front desk.
We'll never let you get away
with your filthy. evil plot.
Oh. no?
Who's gonna stop me?
A feeble. stupid.
-sick woman like you?
-[Grandma coughing]
[chuckling]
Oh. you think that's funny?
Not that.
See. I was just thinking.
Pretty soon. you not gonna
be able to do much of nothing.
And why is that. brave.
little. soon-to-be-dead woman?
The pea soup.
[quietly] The pea soup...
No... No...
No... [whimpering]
[Grand High Witch laughing]
[croakily] You stupid fool.
I did not drink the pea soup.
If you recall.
I was interrupted.
[whispering] Okay.
here's what we're gonna do.
[whispering indistinctly]
[Grand High Witch]
Well. well. well.
Let me see.
I think
I will reach into your chest
and rip out your withered.
shriveled heart.
and squeeze it
until it bursts.
Blah. blah. blah. blah. blah.
All your butt-ugly witch-talk
don't scare me one bit.
It should.
considering the last thing
you will ever see
is my snickering face.
I believe
with every fiber
of my being...
that in the end.
love will always triumph
over hatred and evil.
Is that so?
[Grandma] You may have turned
Alice and my grandson.
but I will make sure
you never turn another child.
So help me. God.
Now!
[grunts]
[screaming]
[Grand High Witch gagging]
[gasps deeply]
[grunts]
-[shuddering]
-[liquid bubbling]
[gobbling convulsively]
-[fizzing]
-[Grand High Witch yelping]
[muffled screaming]
[smoke hissing]
[gasps]
[Mary whimpers]
-[snarling aggressively]
-[gasps]
[snarling continues]
-[gasps] You stupid rat.
-[all screaming]
Look what you've done.
-[Bruno whimpers]
-Run!
Look what you've done.
[snarling]
You stupid rodents.
Get back here!
You filthy pests.
-Yum.
-Parasites.
Kid. I'm gonna get you.
you putrid varmints.
[Grand High Witch yelling]
-[Bruno screams]
-[snarling]
Now I've got you!
[cackles]
What?
I'm done listening
to your trash talk.
What is this?
[grunting]
[Grandma chuckles]
You fool.
Let me out.
-[all grunting]
-Let me out!
Let me out! Let me out!
[screaming]
[both in sing-song]
Nah. nah. nah. nah. nah.
I will rip out your tongues.
Stupid mice.
[Mary in sing-song]
The witch in a bottle...
-[Grand High Witch] Let me out.
-Witch in a bottle...
[Grand High Witch] Let me out
of this stupid fish bowl.
Hey. Grandma. this is the key
to that big trunk.
That's my key.
you pea-brain brat.
-You pea-brain parasites.
-Come on. guys.
Nah. nah... [blows raspberry]
Put your tongue
back in your mouth.
you filthy sewer guttersnipes.
What are you doing?
That is mine.
-[Grandma] Ooh!
-That's mine.
You idiots. You scoundrels.
That is a lot of bacon.
-Lettuce.
-Dough.
Hey. you're making me
terribly hungry.
No. get your hands off
of that. that's mine!
Get your filthy paws
off my filthy lucre.
I'll poke out your beady eyes.
What are you looking at?
What's that. Grandma?
It's a list of names
and addresses
of every witch in the world.
Wow!
With that list and that money
and all this potion.
we could turn every witch
in the world into rats.
Excellent!
[Grand High Witch]
I'll cut off your tails
with rusty scissors.
I'll clip your ears
with toenail clippers.
I'll poke out your beady eyes.
I'll get you for this!
[Grandma] All right.
kiddies. one hop.
-We got work to do.
-[Hades meows]
[Grandma] I almost forgot.
[gasps]
[Grand High Witch]
No. no. no. don't do that.
[voice shaking]
What are you doing?
Hades.
Good pussy.
-You are a good pussy cat.
-[snarling]
Nice kitty.
-You two have fun now.
-Nice kitty.
Ah. you stupid.
mangy fleabag. Precious.
Put the books back.
Stay back.
you stupid. precious...
No! Hades.
Hades. precious.
remember who feeds you.
No. don't think about food.
-[yelps and screams]
-[Hades hissing and yowling]
-[panicked squeaking]
-[Hades continues yowling]
Grandma. you hear that?
I don't know
what you're talking about.
-I didn't hear a thing.
-[Mary giggles]
Oh! Well. thank you kindly.
And one for you.
[older Hero]  The next morning.
we were feeling joyful
and triumphant.
As a matter of fact.
Grandma was so happy.
she was spreading her joy
to the entire hotel staff.
Thank you kindly
for everything.
One for you.
And one for you.
Thank you. ma'am.
[older Hero]
Bruno tried to explain
the situation to his mom.
Hello. Mother.
I'm now a mouse.
[shrieks and gasps]
-[Mrs. Jenkins] It's a mouse!
-[older Hero]  But it turned out
Mr. and Mrs. Jenkins
weren't really mouse people.
So. we decided
it would be best
if Bruno came to stay with me.
Grandma. and Daisy.
[all whooping and cheering]
[Bruno] Faster. faster!
[Mary squealing]
[laughing]
[all screaming happily]
Here we go!
[laughing and cheering]
Whee!
-Cool!
-Whoo-hoo!
[Mary] How's my hair look?
How's my hair?
[laughs] Whoo-hoo!
Whoo-hoo!
-Let's go again. y'all.
-[Grandma chuckles]
[Bruno] This time
I sit in the front.
Grandma. I love being a mouse.
Oh. I believe you do.
But you wanna know
something weird?
I still feel just like a boy.
[Grandma] But you are. darling.
Life changes all of us.
I mean. look at me.
I'm getting on up
in the years.
but I still feel like a girl.
And I still feel like a boy.
See?
You get it.
Never give up
what you are inside.
When I look at you. I don't
see whiskers and a pink nose.
I just see your eyes.
Bright and beautiful.
Grandma.
how long does a mouse live?
Oh. an ordinary mouse
only lives about three years.
but you're no ordinary mouse.
You're a mouse-person.
and a mouse-person
will almost certainly live
three times longer
than an ordinary mouse.
Maybe even longer.
That's great news.
I couldn't stand being
looked after by anybody else.
I'll be a very old mouse
and you'll be
a very old grandmother.
and we'll both die together.
With a little luck. darling.
But no one knows how long
their time is on this earth.
Only God knows that answer.
And that is
the natural order of things.
[older Hero]
Daisy. Bruno. and I
loved living with Grandma.
We were one big. happy family.
[disco music playing]
[camera shutter clicks]
[older Hero]  Where were we?
Oh. yeah. That's right.
So. here we are.
ready to carry on the fight.
[all] Carry on the fight!
Over the years. we have turned
and mouse-afied
every damnable witch
in these United States.
[kids cheering]
So. we are gathered here
to take our battle
to the entire world.
[kids cheering]
-You have your names. correct?
-[kids] Yes. sir.
[older Hero] Your addresses?
[kids] Yes. sir.
And your Number 86
Mouse Maker potion?
[kids] Yes. sir. Number 86
Mouse Maker potion. sir.
Let's get out there
and give those witches
a taste of their own medicine.
[kids cheering]
[Grandma laughing]
[sighs]
So. you ready for this
mission. old-timer?
Grandma.
I've never been more ready.